<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<framenumbers count="3">
<frame id="1">
<framename><![CDATA[Chapter 1]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[Introduction]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to the Influenza Learning System.</p><p>This module on <b>Influenza Vaccines Competitive Landscape</b>, provides an overview of the influenza vaccines currently approved for use in the European Union (EU).</p><p>Before proceeding, read the listed learning objectives.</p><p>After completing this module, you should be able to:</p><ul><li>List the various manufacturers that produce and deliver influenza vaccines in Europe.</li><li>Describe the various influenza vaccines approved in the EU region.</li></ul>]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[]]></information>
</frame>
<frame id="2">
<framename><![CDATA[Chapter 2]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[Influenza Vaccines in the EU]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[<p>The on-screen table summarises the key information about the various influenza vaccines approved for use in the European Union (EU). The influenza vaccine manufacturers producing and delivering the seasonal vaccines in European countries at present are shown in the table on-screen. The vaccines produced are named differently in different countries, despite being the same product.<sup>1</sup> </p><p>We will discuss some of these major vaccines in detail in the following frames.</p>]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[<p></p>]]></information>
</frame>
<frame id="3">
<framename><![CDATA[Chapter 3]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[Overview]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[<p>Influvac is a trivalent inactivated influenza vaccine.6 </p><p>The vaccine is composed of influenza virus surface <b>antigens</b> (haemagglutinin and neuraminidase), of the following strains:
A (H1N1), A (H3N2) and B. The vaccine antigens are propagated in fertilized hens' eggs from healthy chicken flocks.<sup>6</sup> </p><p>For more information on Influvac, click/tap the corresponding tabs.</p>]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[]]></information>
</frame>
<frame id="4">
<framename><![CDATA[Chapter 4]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[Overview]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[<p>Respiration is a process of gas exchange in the body involving four basic steps—pulmonary ventilation, external respiration, transport of respiratory gases, and internal respiration.<sup>1,2</sup> </p><p>These steps ensure exchange of oxygen and carbon dioxide between the external environment and body cells. Continuous supply of oxygen is vital for the body cells to carry out their functions.<sup>2</sup> </p>]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[]]></information>
</frame>
<frame id="5">
<framename><![CDATA[Chapter 5]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[Steps of Respiration]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[<p>Pulmonary ventilation involves the exchange of air between the atmosphere and the lungs and occurs through inhalation and exhalation of air.<sup>1</sup></p><p>External respiration refers to the exchange of gases between the alveoli of the lungs and the blood in the capillaries of the lungs. During this process, oxygen moves into the blood in lung capillaries, while carbon dioxide moves out.<sup>1,2</sup></p><p>The oxygen from the lung capillaries is transported via blood to different organs and tissue cells, and the carbon dioxide from these cells is again transported in a similar fashion to the lung capillaries.<sup>2</sup></p><p>Internal respiration, or tissue respiration, refers to the exchange of gases between the blood in the systemic capillaries and tissue cells. Metabolic processes that occur within the cells are termed as cellular respiration. In cellular respiration, cells use oxygen and release carbon dioxide during the metabolic process of generating energy from nutrient molecules.<sup>1</sup></p> 
</p>]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[]]></information>
</frame>
<frame id="6">
<framename><![CDATA[Chapter 6]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[Nose]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[<p>Let’s first take a look at the anatomy of the upper respiratory tract, which broadly consists of the nose and the pharynx.</p><p>The external portion of the nose has two openings called the nostrils or external nares. The space inside the nose is called the nasal cavity. The anterior portion of the nasal cavity which is situated just inside the nostrils and is surrounded by <b>cartilage</b> is called the <b>nasal vestibule</b>. The superior part of nasal cavity is  surrounded by bone.<sup>1</sup></p><p>The nasal septum separates the nasal cavity into right and left sides. Similar to the nasal cavity, the anterior part of the nasal septum is formed by cartilage, whereas the posterior part is formed by bone.<sup>1</sup></p>]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[]]></information>
</frame>
<frame id="7">
<framename><![CDATA[Chapter 7]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[Functions]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[<p>Before moving on to the next section on the anatomy of the lower respiratory tract, let’s briefly recapitulate the functions of the structures forming the upper airway.</p><p>The nasal cavity and its mucosa along with the paranasal sinuses condition the inhaled air by warming and moistening it. The mucus produced in the cavity and vibrissae filters air from foreign particles. The nasal cavity and sinuses also act as resonating chambers for speech.<sup>2</sup></p><p>Olfaction is performed by receptors in the olfactory epithelium present on the roof of the nasal cavity.<sup>2</sup></p> 
<p>The pharynx acts as a passageway for air and food. The lymphatic tissue housed in the different tonsils provides protection against pathogens and other inhaled antigens.<sup>2</sup></p>]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[]]></information>
</frame>
<frame id="8">
<framename><![CDATA[Chapter 8]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[Organization]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[<p>Let’s now take a look at the major divisions of the nervous system and the <b>autonomic nervous system</b> control of respiration.</p><p>The two primary divisions of the nervous system are the central nervous system (CNS) and the <b>peripheral nervous system</b>. The CNS, consisting of the brain and the spinal cord, is the command center of the nervous system. It interprets all the incoming messages from the body and generates responses to them. The peripheral nervous system primarily consists of the nerves that extend from the brain and spinal cord and link the body and CNS.<sup>10</sup> </p>
<p>The peripheral nervous system has two functional subdivisions—the sensory or afferent division and the motor or efferent division. The efferent or motor division of the peripheral nervous system is further subdivided into the somatic nervous system and the autonomic nervous system.<sup>10</sup></p><p>The autonomic nervous system is functionally divided into sympathetic and parasympathetic divisions, which act on the same muscles or glands but usually exerting opposite effects. As a whole, the autonomic nervous system regulates the body’s involuntary functions, influencing factors such as heart rate or the movement of food through the digestive tract.<sup>10</sup> 
</p>]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[]]></information>
</frame>
    <frame id="9">
<framename><![CDATA[Chapter 9]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[Classification]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[<p>There are two types of adaptive immune responses: antibody-mediated immunity and cell-mediated immunity.<sup>1,3</sup></p><p>Antibody-mediated immunity, also referred to as humoral immunity, involves the production of antibodies by B-cell derivatives known as plasma cells.<sup>1,7</sup> These antibodies circulate in the body and bind to foreign substances, such as bacteria and bacterial toxins, and temporarily inactivate them.<sup>1</sup></p><p>Cell-mediated immunity, on the other hand, involves the production of T cells that either directly attack infected cells or indirectly destroy them by releasing chemical substances that enhance the response mediated by the other immune cells.<sup>1,2</sup></p>]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[]]></information>
</frame>
    <frame id="10">
<framename><![CDATA[Chapter 10]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[Learning Activity]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[<p>You will now be presented with a Quiz.</p>]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[]]></information>
</frame>
    <frame id="11">
<framename><![CDATA[Chapter 11]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[Drag and Drop]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[<p>You will now be presented with a Quiz.</p>]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[]]></information>
</frame>
	<frame id="12">
<framename><![CDATA[Chapter 12]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[Fill in the blanks]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[<p>Quiz</p>]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[]]></information>
</frame>
	<frame id="13">
<framename><![CDATA[Chapter 13]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[End of Module]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[<p>End of Module</p>]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[]]></information>
</frame>
</framenumbers>