<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<framenumbers>
<frame id="1">
<framename><![CDATA[Learning Objectives]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[Introduction]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to the Sanofi Biosurgery Seprafilm<sup>®</sup> Learning System.<br><br>Module 2, <b>Pathophysiology and Complications of Adhesions</b>, discusses the mechanism of adhesion formation and its impact after abdominal surgery, obstetric surgery, and gynecology procedures.<br><br>Before proceeding, read the listed learning objectives.<br><br>Seprafilm<sup>®</sup> has not been demonstrated to reduce or prevent any pelvic disorders other than formation of post-operative adhesions. The information in this module is provided for your background information only. Only approved safety and efficacy claims from the Seprafilm<sup>®</sup> Instructions for use may be discussed in accordance with policy for the US Seprafilm<sup>®</sup> Sales Professional.</p>]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[<p></p>]]></information>
</frame>
<frame id="2">
<framename><![CDATA[Introduction]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[Adhesions]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[<p>Trauma to intraperitoneal organs can result in adhesion formation.[1]<br><br>Trauma-related adhesions may result from tissue injuries occurring during surgeries, abdominal and pelvic therapies, or diseases. The formation of fibrous connections between tissues and organs may occur during the first week of the healing process.[1-3]</p>]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[]]></information>
</frame>
<frame id="3">
<framename><![CDATA[Incidence]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[Postsurgical Adhesions]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[<p>The incidence of postsurgical adhesions following abdominal surgery has been reported to be between 67% and 93%.[4]<br><br>In a 10-year follow-up study conducted in 12,584 patients who underwent lower abdominal surgery, it was noted that 7.3% of readmissions were directly related to adhesions.[5]<br><br>It was also found in the study that 25.4% of readmissions were due to a potential <span style="white-space:nowrap">adhesion-related</span> disorder during the first postoperative year.[5]<br><br>Let’s now discuss incidence of postsurgical adhesions in pelvic procedures. The incidence of intraperitoneal postsurgical adhesions following pelvic surgery in women has been reported to be between 55% and 100%.[6]<br><br>The most common site of adhesion formation among gynecologic procedures is the ovaries, and they contribute to the highest readmission rate due to adhesions.[1,7]<br><br>It has been reported that up to 20% of the patients undergoing open gynecologic surgery are readmitted within 1 year for an additional open gynecologic procedure that may be complicated by adhesions.[1]<br><br>Data indicate that the presence and severity of adhesions increase with each subsequent cesarean delivery.[9]<br><br>The efficacy and safety of Seprafilm<sup>®</sup>, in relation to reduction of adhesions in cesarean section, has not been confirmed in <span style="white-space:nowrap">well-controlled</span> clinical trials.[8]</p>]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[]]></information>
</frame>
<frame id="4">
<framename><![CDATA[Etiology]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[<p>Pelvic adhesions can form as a result of inflammation, <b>endometriosis</b>, or surgical trauma. Any surgical procedure can cause adhesion formation and is independent of a surgeon’s ability or the technique used.[10]<br><br>There are several factors contributing to postsurgical adhesions, which may include tissue manipulation, desiccation, contact with blood, abrasion, heat or <b>electrocautery</b>, foreign particles, suturing, and infection.[1,6,11]<br><br>The safety and effectiveness of Seprafilm<sup>®</sup> Adhesion Barrier has not been evaluated in clinical studies in the presence of frank infections in the abdominopelvic cavity. Seprafilm Adhesion Barrier did not promote the growth of test microorganisms within the abdominopelvic cavity in animal studies.[8]<br><br>Click/Tap the tabs to learn more about the etiology of postsurgical adhesions.<br><br>Tissue manipulation is the process in which surgeons manipulate organs and other tissues during surgery, only to move them out of the way. Even the slightest tissue abrasion can damage the mesothelium and cause the peritoneal healing process to begin, thus leading to adhesion formation.[1,6]<br><br>During surgery, mesothelial tissue, which is normally kept moist when the body is closed, is exposed to the drying effect of air. This condition is known as desiccation, which is one of the causes for postsurgical adhesions.<br><br>The tissue may also come into contact with blood during surgery. This increases the available amount of fibrin at the surface of the damaged tissue, and white blood cells exacerbate the inflammatory response, precipitating adhesion formation.[6]<br><br>Abrasion or sharp trauma to the peritoneum disrupts the confluent layer of mesothelial cells, leading to postsurgical adhesion formation.[6]<br><br>Many surgical procedures involve the use of electrically generated heat to cauterize bleeding vessels or to cut tissues. Thermal injuries can lead to both ischemia and inflammation, which in turn results in adhesion formation.[6]<br><br>Although surgical supplies are sterile, surface particles can adhere to the operative site. For example, starch used to lubricate surgical gloves, lint from swabs, and paper fibers from gowns can trigger an inflammatory response, leading to adhesion formation.[6]<br><br>Whenever sutures or staples are placed in the peritoneum, blood flow to the peritoneum can be compromised if the sutures are too tight, or the sutures may provoke a foreign body reaction, precipitating adhesion formation.[6]<br><br>Infection and inflammatory disease may result in adhesion formation.[6]</p> 
</p>]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[]]></information>
</frame>
<frame id="5">
<framename><![CDATA[Pathophysiology]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[<p>The postsurgical healing mechanism in the peritoneal cavity occurs by a combination of mesothelial regeneration and <b>fibrosis</b>, resulting in adhesion formation between the damaged serosal surfaces. This process occurs in a chronological sequence and typically spans 7 days.[1,6]<br><br>
After tissue trauma, on day 1, inflammation brings macrophages (inflammatory cells and a major source of growth factors for many cell types; they stimulate mesothelial cell proliferation on the surface of a wound) and <b>fibroblasts</b> to the surface of the wound. A fibrin (insoluble blood protein from fibrinogen; essential structural element of blood clots and early postsurgical adhesions) matrix develops between the adhesiogenic tissue surfaces not covered by a mesothelial cell layer.[1,3,6]<br><br>On day 3, macrophages form the foundation of the advancing adhesion. Fibrin matrix advancement occurs with the proliferation of fibroblasts and vascularization.[3]<br><br>By day 5, the advancing adhesion will be increasingly vascular and organized in structure.[3]<br><br>No new adhesions are likely to develop after day 7.[3]</p>]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[]]></information>
</frame>
<frame id="6">
<framename><![CDATA[Quiz]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[Learning Activity]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[<p>You will now be presented with a learning activity.</p>]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[]]></information>
</frame>
<frame id="7">
<framename><![CDATA[Not an Adhesion Barrier]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[Omentum]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[<p>Preventing mechanical contact by the use of inert physical materials between the serosal surfaces for >3 days, theoretically may help prevent adhesion formation, thus allowing mesothelial healing independently.[12]<br><br>The <b>omentum</b> or peritoneal grafts could prove to be a natural and cheap method to cover raw deperitonized areas. However, this is not practical owing to the fact that the raw areas may be too large or may not be accessible. In addition, they interfere with <b>ovulation</b> or oocyte pickup.[12,13]<br><br>Finally, the omentum may also adhere to traumatized tissues on either side (midline incision above the omentum and small bowel under the omentum).[4]</p>]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[]]></information>
</frame>
    <frame id="8">
<framename><![CDATA[Clinical Impact]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[<p>In a study conducted in 552 patients admitted for small bowel obstruction (SBO), adhesions were reported to be the cause of obstruction in 74% of the patients.[14]<br><br>A pivotal study conducted by Becker et al (1996) showed omental adhesions in 79% of the untreated control patients.[4]<br><br>Most surgeons performing colorectal procedures choose to leave the peritoneum open as suturing of the peritoneum when closing the abdomen is associated with suboptimal healing.[4,15]<br><br>The Becker et al study (1996) showed that despite an intact omentum in all patients in the control group, a portion of the small intestine adhered to the midline incision in 63% of cases.[4]<br><br>When interacting with Health Care Professionals, you must discuss <i>all three</i> points related to SBO reduction included in the Clinical Studies Section of Seprafilm’s <span style="white-space:nowrap">FDA-approved</span> labeling. Specifically, in a <span style="white-space:nowrap">post-approval</span> study of Seprafilm<sup>®</sup> of 1791 patients undergoing adhesiolysis for existing SBO:<br><br>Using protocol defined criteria, 15 of the 840 intestinal resection patients (1.8%) in the Seprafilm<sup>®</sup> group experienced an adhesive SBO that required reoperation compared to 29 of 861 intestinal resection patients (3.4%) in the control group (p<0.05).[16,17]<br><br>When all cases of bowel obstruction were considered, including those in which bowel obstruction could not be ruled out, 109 of 888 patients (12%) in the Seprafilm<sup>®</sup> group and 106 of 903 patients (12%) in the control group had bowel obstruction.[16,17]<br><br>Of the 90 patients with existing bowel obstructions, no significant difference in incidence of adhesive SBO requiring reoperation was found (3 of the 48 Seprafilm<sup>®</sup> patients versus 1 of 42 control patients).<span style="white-space:nowrap">[16,17]</span></p>]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[]]></information>
</frame>
    <frame id="9">
<framename><![CDATA[]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[Learning Activity]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[<p>You will now be presented with a learning activity.</p>]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[]]></information>
</frame>
    <frame id="10">
<framename><![CDATA[Introduction]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[Impact of Postsurgical Adhesions]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[Postsurgical adhesions may contribute to significant morbidity and complications such as intestinal obstruction, chronic pelvic pain, infertility, dyspareunia (difficult or painful sexual intercourse) following general abdominal or gynecologic surgery, and complexity during <span style="white-space:nowrap">reoperation.[3]</span><br><br>Such complications may require secondary surgical intervention.<br><br>Although a single thin adhesive band can cause complications, greater area coverage and greater adhesion density are associated with a higher risk of adhesion-related <span style="white-space:nowrap">complications.[7]</span><br><br>Seprafilm<sup>®</sup> has not been demonstrated to reduce or prevent any pelvic disorders other than formation of post-operative adhesions.]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[]]></information>
</frame>
    <frame id="11">
<framename><![CDATA[Surgeon’s Ability]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[It has been proposed that the real extent of adhesions and adhesion-related complications is underestimated by most surgeons. It could be due to various factors. Years after a procedure, adhesive complications occur unpredictably and are treated by physicians or specialists other than the initial operating surgeon. In addition, etiology of adhesion formation is still incompletely understood. Adhesions remain undiagnosed in most cases as they may be asymptomatic.[18]]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[]]></information>
</frame>
    <frame id="12">
<framename><![CDATA[Small Bowel Obstruction]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[Let’s now focus on the complications of postsurgical adhesions following abdominal surgery. We will begin with SBO.<br><br>SBO is a blockage of the small intestine. Adhesions are the most common cause of SBO. Multiple studies have shown that adhesions may be the cause of 65% to 75% of SBO cases.[1,7]<br><br>An SBO event caused by an adhesion can be referred to as adhesive small bowel obstruction (ASBO).[2]<br><br>Adhesions that extend between the bowel and the adjacent structures may restrict mobility and the natural flow of bowel contents. Therefore, SBO is the most serious <span style="white-space:nowrap">adhesion-related</span> complication with a 10% risk of mortality if not diagnosed and treated immediately.[19]<br><br>Except for ASBO cases requiring reoperation, there is limited data indicates that the use of Seprafilm<sup>®</sup> can reduce complications of adhesions or other comorbid conditions associated with them especially when comparing them with a control group that did not use <span style="white-space:nowrap">Seprafilm<sup>®</sup>.[3]</span><br><br>Using the protocol-defined criteria, 15 of the 840 intestinal resection patients (1.8%) in the Seprafilm<sup>®</sup> group experienced an ASBO that required reoperation compared with 29 of the 861 intestinal resection patients (3.4%) in the control group (<i>P</i><.05). When all cases of bowel obstruction were considered, including those in which bowel obstruction could not be ruled out, 109 of 888 patients (12%) in the Seprafilm<sup>®</sup> group and 106 of 903 patients (12%) in the control group had bowel obstruction. Of the 90 patients with existing bowel obstructions, no significant difference in incidence of ASBO requiring reoperation was found (3 of the 48 Seprafilm<sup>®</sup>-treated patients versus 1 of 42 control patients).[8]<br><br>Promotional messaging around Seprafilm<sup>®</sup> should solely focus on reduction of adhesion with appropriate balancing safety information.<br><br>When interacting with Health Care Professionals, you must discuss <i>all three</i> points related to SBO reduction included in the Clinical Studies Section of Seprafilm’s <span style="white-space:nowrap">FDA-approved</span> labeling. Specifically, in a <span style="white-space:nowrap">post-approval</span> study of Seprafilm<sup>®</sup> of 1791 patients undergoing adhesiolysis for existing SBO:<br><br>Using protocol defined criteria, 15 of the 840 intestinal resection patients (1.8%) in the Seprafilm<sup>®</sup> group experienced an adhesive SBO that required reoperation compared to 29 of 861 intestinal resection patients (3.4%) in the control group (<i>p</i><0.05).[16,17]<br><br>When all cases of bowel obstruction were considered, including those in which bowel obstruction could not be ruled out, 109 of 888 patients (12%) in the Seprafilm<sup>®</sup> group and 106 of 903 patients (12%) in the control group had bowel obstruction.[16,17]<br><br>Of the 90 patients with existing bowel obstructions, no significant difference in incidence of adhesive SBO requiring reoperation was found (3 of the 48 Seprafilm<sup>®</sup> patients versus 1 of 42 control patients).[16,17] ]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[]]></information>
</frame>
    <frame id="13">
<framename><![CDATA[SBO-Impact on the Surgeon]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[A patient with ASBO can be an emergency patient, who presents to the general surgeon with pain.[15]<br><br>Even if surgery is not required to relieve pain associated with ASBO, discomfort, time in the hospital, recurrence rate, and shorter readmission time are issues to be <span style="white-space:nowrap">considered.[15]</span><br><br>It has been reported that up to 20% of patients undergoing open abdominal surgery are readmitted within 2 years for an additional open abdominal procedure that may be complicated by adhesions.[1]<br><br>Moreover, clinical reports suggest that about 1 in 6 colorectal resection patients are readmitted within 2 years for intestinal obstruction and are treated surgically.[3]<br><br>A study by Ellis et al showed that 36.5% abdominal adhesion-related readmission were due to SBO.[20]<br><br>Post-approval study showed that Seprafilm<sup>®</sup> has no impact on the incidence of small bowel obstruction (SBO) generally.<br><br>Post-approval study showed that Seprafilm<sup>®</sup> reduces the incidence of adhesive SBO requiring reoperation.<br><br>Post-approval study showed that in patients with existing bowel adhesions, Seprafilm<sup>®</sup> has no impact on the incidence of adhesive SBO requiring reoperation.]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[]]></information>
</frame>
    <frame id="14">
<framename><![CDATA[Infertility]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[<p>Adhesions can be a significant cause of infertility.[1] As the unfertilized egg is released from the ovaries, it is captured by the <b>fimbriae</b>, the finger-like projections at the end of the fallopian tubes. The fimbriae sweep the egg into the openings of the fallopian tubes.[21] <br><br>
Adhesions may interfere with the ability of the fimbriae to pick up eggs and restrict the freedom of the ovaries and fallopian tubes, thereby leading to infertility.[7]<br><br>The effect of Seprafilm<sup>®</sup> on long-term clinical outcomes such as chronic pain and infertility has not been determined in clinical studies.[8]</p>]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[]]></information>
</frame>
    <frame id="15">
<framename><![CDATA[Chronic Pelvic Pain]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[<p>Chronic pelvic pain can often be attributed to adhesions. This is because adhesions tend to restrict free movement of pelvic organs. Nerves and pain neurochemicals have been identified within adhesion tissue samples.[1]<br><br>About 26% to 48% of adhesion incidences among patients with chronic pelvic pain do not involve any causative role.[22]<br><br>Patients with chronic pain make frequent visits to the doctor for additional treatments for pain reduction.<br><br>Click/Tap the video icon to learn more.</p>]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[]]></information>
</frame>
    <frame id="16">
<framename><![CDATA[Impact on the Surgeon]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[Complexity During Reoperation]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[Surgery-related medical complications involving adhesions include inadvertent <b>enterotomy</b> and increased reentry time. An inadvertent enterotomy is an accidental incision through the full thickness of the bowel wall. This has been reported to occur up to 19% more frequently when adhesions are present.[23]<br><br>Adhesions from a previous procedure increase the time to re-enter the abdomen and to divide all adhesions. Operative times can be prolonged due to difficulties <span style="white-space:nowrap">re-entering</span> the abdomen if patients have adhesions from previous surgical procedures, however Seprafilm<sup>®</sup> has not been demonstrated to reduce operative times in these patients.[24]]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[]]></information>
</frame>
    <frame id="17">
<framename><![CDATA[Chapter 11]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[Drag and Drop]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[<p>You will now be presented with a learning activity.</p>]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[]]></information>
</frame>
    <frame id="18">
<framename><![CDATA[Chapter 11]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[Drag and Drop]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[Let us discuss the key highlights of this module.<br><br>Intraperitoneal trauma can result in adhesion formation.<br><br>The incidence of postsurgical adhesions following abdominal surgery has been reported to be between 67 and 93%.<br><br>The incidence of intraperitoneal postsurgical adhesions following pelvic surgery in women has been reported to be between 55% and 100%.<br><br>
The most common site of adhesion formation among gynecologic procedures is at the ovaries, and they contribute to the highest readmission rate due to adhesions.<br><br>Presence and severity of adhesions increases with each subsequent cesarean delivery.<br><br>Factors contributing to postsurgical adhesions include tissue manipulation, desiccation, contact with blood, abrasion, heat or electrocautery, foreign particles, suturing, and infection.<br><br>The safety and effectiveness of Seprafilm<sup>®</sup> Adhesion Barrier has not been evaluated in clinical studies in the presence of frank infections in the abdominopelvic cavity. Seprafilm<sup>®</sup> Adhesion Barrier did not promote the growth of test microorganisms within the abdominopelvic cavity in animal studies.<br><br>Postsurgical adhesions may contribute to significant morbidity and complications such as intestinal obstruction, chronic pelvic pain, infertility, dyspareunia (difficult or painful sexual intercourse) following general abdominal or gynecologic surgery, and complexity during reoperation.<br><br>Seprafilm<sup>®</sup> has not been demonstrated to reduce or prevent any pelvic disorders other than formation of post-operative adhesions.<br><br> SBO is a blockage of the small intestine. Adhesions are the most common cause of SBO.<br><br>It has been reported that up to 20% of patients undergoing open gynecologic surgery are readmitted within 1 year for an additional open gynecologic procedure that may be complicated by adhesions.<br><br>Multiple studies have shown that adhesions may be the cause of 65% to 75% of SBO cases.<br><br>Adhesions may interfere with the ability of the fimbriae to pick up eggs, as well as restrict the freedom of ovaries and fallopian tubes thereby leading to infertility.<br><br>Chronic pelvic pain is often attributable to adhesions, because of the restriction of free movement of pelvic organs.<br><br>Surgery-related medical complications involving adhesions include inadvertent enterotomy and increased re-entry time.
]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[]]></information>
</frame>
	<frame id="19">
<framename><![CDATA[Chapter 12]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[End of Module]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[<p>End of Module</p>]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[]]></information>
</frame>
</framenumbers>