<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<framenumbers count="3">
<frame id="1">
<framename><![CDATA[Chapter 1]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[Introduction]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to the Ipsen Somatuline e-learning programme.</p><p>Module 3, NETs Overview: Classification, Diagnosis and Therapeutic Management, provides a brief overview on neuroendocrine tumours (NETs) and the key clinical trials conducted to assess treatment of NETs. This module is divided into 3 sections.</p><p>The first section discusses the disease characteristics of neuroendocrine neoplasms (NENs), with a special attention to gastroentero-pancreatic (GEP) NETs. It also discusses the classification and grading of NETs according to European Neuroendocrine Tumour Society (ENETS) and World Health Organization (WHO) and describes the various diagnostic methods used to detect these diseases.</p><p>The second section provides a detailed account of the treatment strategies for GEP-NETs.</p><p>The third section focuses on the clinical trials that highlight and compare the different treatment strategies for GEP-NETs.</p><p>Before proceeding, read the listed learning objectives.</p><p><strong>Note:</strong> At any time, you can navigate through the module by clicking the menu button displayed at the bottom of the screen. You do not have to go through all the topics discussed, and can revisit a section as many times as required.</p>]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[]]></information>
</frame>
<frame id="2">
<framename><![CDATA[Chapter 2]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[Neuroendocrine]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[<p>Neuroendocrine neoplasms (NENs) are tumours that originate from neuroendocrine cells located in various parts of the body.1 They are a diverse group of malignant tumours with some common features; however, not all exhibit hypersecretion of peptide hormones and related symptoms.<sup>1</sup> They specifically express the neuroendocrine markers in the tumour cells. NENs comprise low-, intermediate- and high-grade tumours.<sup>2</sup> </p><p>According to the ENETS 2011 guidelines, the low- to intermediate-grade neoplasms are defined as NETs that were previously classified as carcinoid or atypical carcinoid. Atypical carcinoid is an intermediate form of NET varying between typical carcinoid (low-grade) and small cell carcinoma (high-grade). The high-grade tumours are defined as neuroendocrine carcinoma (NEC), which was previously known as poorly differentiated carcinoma.<sup>2</sup></p>]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[<p>NETs are complex and heterogeneous in nature, originating most commonly from the GEP tract and from the pulmonary system.3, 4 Approximately 60% of NETs are localised within the GEP tract, and the remaining are located mainly in the lungs (25% of NETs) and in the thymus as well as in the parathyroid, adrenal and pituitary glands.<sup>3, 5</sup> 
</p>]]></information>
</frame>
<frame id="3">
<framename><![CDATA[Chapter 3]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[Tabs]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[<p>Hello</p><ul><li>Hi Dummy text 3 </li></ul>]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[]]></information>
</frame>
<frame id="4">
<framename><![CDATA[Chapter 4]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[Tabs feature V2]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[<p>Hello</p><ul><li>Hi Dummy text 4 </li></ul>]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[]]></information>
</frame>
<frame id="5">
<framename><![CDATA[Chapter 5]]></framename>
<sectionname><![CDATA[Tabs feature V3]]></sectionname>
<audiotranscript><![CDATA[<p>Hello</p><ul><li>Hi Dummy text 5 </li></ul>]]></audiotranscript>
<information><![CDATA[]]></information>
</frame>
</framenumbers>