<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<audiotranscripts>
  <audioframe id="1">
    <audiotranscript>Influenza, commonly known as "the flu", is an infectious disease caused by the influenza virus. Symptoms can be mild to severe. The most common symptoms include: a high fever, runny nose, sore throat, muscle pains, headache, coughing, and feeling tired.These symptoms typically begin two days after exposure to the virus and most last less than a week. The cough, however, may last for more than two weeks.In children there may be nausea and vomiting but these are not common in adults. Nausea and vomiting occur more commonly in the unrelated infection gastroenteritis, which is sometimes inaccurately referred to as "stomach flu" or "24-hour flu".Complications of influenza may include viral pneumonia, secondary bacterial pneumonia, sinus infections, and worsening of previous health problems such as asthma or heart failure.</audiotranscript>
	<refnumber>21</refnumber>
  </audioframe>
  <audioframe id="2">
    <audiotranscript>Influenza A and B, viruses can be further characterized into strains. There is a plethora of different strains of influenza B viruses and of influenza A subtypes, and new strains of influenza viruses can appear and replace older strains. Such newly emerging viruses contain antigenic variations known as antigenic drift and shift. The clinical outcome of the disease depends on both the influenza virus and ensuing host defense.</audiotranscript>
		<refnumber>24</refnumber>
  </audioframe>
  <audioframe id="3">
    <audiotranscript>Usually, the virus is spread through the air from coughs or sneezes. This is believed to occur mostly over relatively short distances. It can also be spread by touching surfaces contaminated by the virus and then touching the mouth or eyes. A person may be infectious to others both before and during the time they are sick. The infection may be confirmed by testing the throat, sputum, or nose for the virus.</audiotranscript>
	<refnumber>41</refnumber>
  </audioframe>
  <audioframe id="4">
    <audiotranscript>The infection may be confirmed by testing the throat, sputum, or nose for the virus.</audiotranscript>
	<refnumber>42</refnumber>
  </audioframe>
</audiotranscripts>